(飛段)いてぇだろ…？ なぁ？
It hurts, doesn't it?
Well?
The judgment has been
handed down.
(飛段)裁きが下ったな。
(イズモ)ど… どういうことだ!?
Wh-What do you mean?
(飛段)どうだ？ 少しは
他人の痛みが 理解できたか？
How about it?
Has this helped you understand
the pain that other people feel,
even a little bit?
《アスマ : オレの腕まで…。
ヤツの術か何かか？ いや…》
Even my arm...
Has his Jutsu done something?
No, that can't be...
(飛段)すでに テメエは
オレに呪われた。
You have already fallen
under my curse.
これより 儀式を始める。
The ceremony will now begin.
ハハハハ…。
さぁ… オレと一緒に
最高の痛みを味わおうぜ！
Well, then...
Why not taste the ultimate pain
with me?!
you've gotta be extra careful
mijika ni aru mono
with the things nearest to you
tsuneni ki wo tsukete inai to
you know the closer you get to something
amari ni chika sugite
the tougher it is to see it
miushinatte shimai sou
explain to me this happiness
anata ga saikin taiken shita
that you just got to experience?
shiawase wa ittai nan desu ka
or maybe you're so blessed
megumare sugite ite
that you can't even remember it
omoidasenai kamo
that you stand here now
ima koko ni iru koto
that you still live and breathe
iki wo shite iru koto
I realised that they all were miracles
tada soredake no koto ga
just by themselves
kiseki da to kidzuku
you've gotta be extra careful
mijika ni aru mono
with the things nearest to you
tsuneni ki wo tsukete inai to
you know the closer you get to something
amari ni chika sugite
the tougher it is to see it
miushinatte shimai sou
you know the closer you get to something
the tougher it is to see it
and i'll never take it for granted
it's fine to say you'll never give up
oi tsudzukete kita yume
and to keep chasing your dreams
akiramezu ni susumeyo nante
but the more time you spend talking big
kirei goto wo ieru hodo
the less you get done
nanimo dekicha inai kedo
I will press that handful of courage against my heart
hito nigiri no yuuki wo mune ni
and with its help survive another day
ashita wo ikinuku tame ni
and i'll never take it for granted
let's go
The Judgment
You have already fallen
under my curse.
すでに テメエは オレに呪われた。
これより 儀式を始める。
The ceremony will now begin.
Well, then! Why not taste
the ultimate pain with me?!
さぁ… オレと一緒に
最高の痛みを味わおうぜ！
Why is Captain Asuma burned?
どうして アスマ隊長が ヤケドを!?
Wasn't his opponent the one hit
by the Fire Style Jutsu?!
火遁をくらったのは
ヤツのほうじゃないのか!?
He definitely was hit.
(コテツ)ヤツも くらっている。
But for some reason,
だが どういうわけか
アスマ隊長も 術をくらったんだ。
Captain Asuma was also
burned by the Jutsu!
This... could it be that...
(シカマル)これって まさか…。
This will net us 35 million in gold.
《角都 : これで 3,500万両も
いただきだ》
クハハハー！
All the preparations are
now complete!
これで すべての準備は整った！
ムチャクチャいてぇから 覚悟しろよ！
It's going to hurt like crazy,
so get ready!
Take that!
くらえっ！
うおっ！
It hurts, doesn't it?!
(飛段)いてぇだろ！ ハーッハッハッハ！
But this is nothing.
I haven't got you in a vital spot yet!
急所は こんなもんじゃねえぞ！
アーッハッハッハ！
Believe me,
THAT pain is out of this world!
だが あの痛みは 最高だ。
The pain another feels while
dying penetrates into my own body!
他人が死ぬときの痛みが
オレの体のなかに染みこんでくる！
I pass through the pain, transcend it,
and turn it into pleasure!
痛みを通り越して
快感に変わる～っ！ ハッハー！
アーッハッハ！
Captain Asuma...
アスマ隊長…
左足を押さえてるよな？
is holding his left leg.
Something strange is going on.
やっぱり おかしいぞ。
It's the same injured leg as
ヤツが… 自分で
突き刺したほうの足だ！
the opponent who stabbed himself
with his own lance!
Wh-Why...
くっ… どうして…。
You have already fallen
under my curse.
((飛段 : すでに テメエは
オレに呪われた))
So that's how it is!
そうか！
But of course...
《アスマ : なるほど…。
ヤツの体と オレの体は➡
His body and mine are connected
with some curse.
なんらかの仕掛けで繋がってる。
In other words, the damage dealt
to our bodies is also linked.
つまり 体に受けたダメージも
同じように リンクする…。
Furthermore, he is immortal.
ただし… ヤツは 不死身》
クーッフッフッフ！
Where would you like to hurt next?
次は どこの痛みを味わいたい？
ここか？ ここか？
Hmm? Here? Or here?
How about both legs
at the same time?!
両足ってのもいいよなぁ… アハハ！
Or...
それとも…。
shall we end now?!
もう 終わりにするか!? なぁ!?
How about it?!
Shikamaru! You must not use
a physical attack like Shadow Sewing!
シカマル！
物理攻撃の影縫いは ダメだ！
Stop his movements with
Shadow Strangle Jutsu! Hurry!
影首縛りで ヤツの動きを止めろ！
急げ！
I'm already on it!
もうやってる！
Better make it in time!
《間に合え！》
Please make it in time!
《シカマル : 間に合ってくれ！》
Die!
死ね～っ!!
Do you think I'd let that happen?!
させるかっ!!
(イズモ)よくやったぞ シカマル！
You did it, Shikamaru!
チッ！
(飛段)フッ こんなもん！ フンッ！
This won't stop me for long!
イズモ バックアップを要請してから
何分経ってる？
Izumo, how many minutes have passed
since you requested backup?
10分程度だ。
About ten minutes.
増援が来るには
まだ 20分はかかる。
It'll be at least another 20 minutes
before reinforcements arrive.
そうか…。
That long?!
クソッ どうすりゃいいんだ!?
アイツをやれば アスマ隊長も…。
Damn...! What should we do?!
If we kill him,
Captain Asuma will also die!
効果が持続するタイプの術を解くには
相手を殺すのが セオリーだ。
Usually, one must kill one's opponent
in order to break a long-lasting type Jutsu.
なのに それが
できないとなると…。
But if that is not possible...
術には 必ず 何かしらのルールや➡
Every Jutsu inevitably has rules
associated with it,
用いるためのリスク… 穴がある。
as well as risks and pitfalls.
《シカマル : まずは 冷静になって
相手を分析するんだ…》
First, I need to calm down
and analyze the opponent.
《シカマルに 助けられたな…。
I was saved,
thanks to Shikamaru.
このスキに オレは
この術を解く術を考えねえと…》
I must take this chance and
think of a way to break this Jutsu.
うお～!!
チィ！
(飛段)うお～!!
うぅ！
《アイツ相手に
影首縛りは そうもたん。
With him as an opponent,
the Shadow Strangle Jutsu
won't hold out that long.
考量時間は わずかだ…》
There's little time to consider
the next move.
(角都)長引くようなら
オレもやるぞ。
If this wears on any longer, I'll lend a hand.
大金を逃すわけには
いかんからな。
We can't let all the money get away.
テメエは 引っ込んでろって
言ったろうが 角都！
I told you to butt out, Kakuzu!
うぅ… オレは １人で十分だぜ！
I can handle this...!
(角都)フン…。
《正直 この状況…。
Truth be told, the situation as it is...
もう一人が 攻撃してこないのは
ラッキーだった》
we're lucky the other guy has
stayed out of the fight for now.
《だからといって
どうすればいいのか…》
Be that as it may,
there's still the question of what to do.
《まぁ あとは時間の問題か…》
Well, it's all a matter of time now...
うん？
《アイツ…》
Why that...
《…そうだ 思い出せ！
That's it... Think back...
オレは 想定外の敵と戦う想定を
してきたはずじゃないか…》
Surely, I've come this far assuming
I'd be fighting against an adversary
beyond the scope of my imagination.
((シカマル : 暁の構成メンバーは 10人。
"OROCHIMARU"
The Akatsuki Organization
is made up of ten members.
だが 大蛇丸は 脱退…。
But Orochimaru withdrew.
赤砂のサソリは 死亡…。
Sasori of the Red Sand is dead.
Of the remaining ones,
we know the identities of three.
残りで わかってるのは ３人。
ガイ先生と 余裕で
やりあったっていう干柿 鬼鮫。
"KISAME"
Hoshigaki Kisame,
who is reputed to have sparred
with Guy-sensei with ease...
コイツは 水遁使いか…。
He might be a Water Style User.
サスケの兄貴 写輪眼を持つ
うちは イタチ。
"ITACHI"
Sasuke's older brother,
Uchiha Itachi with his Sharingan...
あのカカシさんが 一週間以上も
入院させられたのは➡
It was his handiwork that put Kakashi-san
in the hospital for over a week.
コイツの仕業だ…。
こっちは
ナルトが やりあったっていう➡
Deidara, said to have sparred
with Naruto.
自在に動く 起爆粘土を使う
デイダラ…。
He uses animated explosive clay.
最後には 自爆だと？
"DEIDARA"
He blew himself up in the end.
It's doubtful whether that story
is actually true.
本当かどうか
怪しいもんだぜ…。
《残る暁は ５人…。
That leaves five members
of the Akatsuki Organization...
Whichever of the faces
in this file you pick,
このファイルに載ってるメンツの
誰をとっても➡
一筋縄の相手じゃねえ。
you'll find him to be one tough opponent.
忍術が どうこうなんて
レベルじゃねえぜ。
Their Ninjutsu will be of a level
that should not be underestimated.
正体のわからない
５人に関しても➡
Though the true nature of
these five is unknown,
there is no doubt they have special abilities
that are beyond our imagination.
想像もつかないような
特殊能力者たちに違いない…》
まったく
とんでもねえ連中だぜ。
Good grief.
"RECORD OF PAST BATTLES"
We're up against the worst possible
bunch of fellows.
これじゃあ 対策なんて➡
When it comes to this,
最初から立てておいても
意味がねえ。
it's meaningless to formulate
a strategy in advance.
むしろ 先入観が
状況を悪化させかねねえ。
In fact, any preconceptions
might make matters worse.
《じゃあ どうする？
So, what should we do?
修行して 強くなるのは
当たり前として➡
It goes without saying that
we should train to get stronger,
それでも勝てねえ敵と
出くわしたら どうする？》
but what happens when you encounter
an adversary against whom
you cannot win?
《敵の能力 力量の分析
忍術 体術 幻術…。
The nature and extent of
the enemy's powers--
his Ninjutsu, Taijutsu, and Genjutsu.
術者のタイプの見極め。
You must discern what type
of Ninja he is.
ツーマンセルの ヤツらの連携攻撃の有無
…可能性。
Then you need to determine whether
or not it's a combined attack
by guys who function as a two-man cell.
And if there's a possibility of that,
味方のチームとの相性…。
then what kind of chemistry does
he have with his team members?
１つでも 多くの情報を得て➡
We need to gather as
much information as possible
瞬時に判断しなくちゃ
ならねえってことか…》
and make a split second decision.
はぁ… 暁みてぇなのが相手じゃ➡
When you're up against an organization
like the Akatsuki,
情報を得る時間なんて
もらえねえだろうなぁ…。
there isn't even time to
gather such information, is there?
(アスマ)暁だと？
Akatsuki, you say?
…アスマ。
Asuma...
もう暁の対策を立てているのか？
Have you already taken action
against the Akatsuki Organization?
(シカマル)いや ムダだって結論に
至ったとこっすよ。
No, I came to the conclusion that
it was pointless.
お前のことだ。
That's what you think.
何か １つでも
敵の情報をつかめば➡
If you got hold of even one piece
of information about the enemy,
策の１つくらい 浮かぶだろうが。
it could lead to a successful strategy.
その情報が つかめればね…。
If we could get our hands
on such information.
初対面の 暁相手じゃ
それも 難しい。
That's difficult since we're up
against the Akatsuki for the first time.
オレなんて
一瞬でやられちまいますよ。
A guy like me would be blown away
in an instant.
(アスマ)まぁ そうだろうな。
Well, you're probably right about that.
"RECORD OF PAST BATTLES
CLASSIFIED DATA VOL. 1"
(シカマル)チェッ 悔しいけど
ヤツら 半端ないっすからね。
It's mortifying,
but those are guys who don't slack off.
お前が 一対一で
暁と当たったのならな…。
That is if you were to come up against
the Akatsuki on a one-to-one basis.
お前の状況判断と 分析力は
木ノ葉でも 屈指のものだ。
You are one of the best at judging
and analyzing a situation,
even among the Hidden Leaf.
一対一で その時間を作れないなら
仲間を頼れ。
If you can't find the time to strategize
in a one-on-one combat,
then depend upon your comrades.
チームの責任は 重要だが
仲間を頼らない者も➡
Team responsibility is important,
but one who does not rely
upon his comrades...
KISAME
その責任を
果たしていないことになる。
is not fulfilling that responsibility.
お前１人で ムリでも➡
There are times when even
if you can't do it alone,
things will somehow work out
仲間が 力を合わせれば
なんとかなるときもある。
if you and your comrades
pool each others strengths.
なんとかなるじゃ
ダメなんですよ。
It's not enough for things to
just somehow work out.
Then, do something.
(じゃ なんとかしろ。
仲間が やられる前にな))
Before your comrades get done in.
《アスマは 多くの情報を
オレに残してくれたんだ！
Asuma has left me with
a wealth of information.
考えろ… 考えるんだ！》
Think! You've got to think!
Remarks, personality, speech patterns...
the clothes they wear...
《発言 性格 口調のパターン…。
身につけているもの
さっきまでの行動の把握…。
Grasp their movements
right up to now.
もろもろの行動の意味…。
The significance of
each and every action.
And then the connection between actions.
そして 行動と 行動の関連性…。
そのすべてから 導くことのできる
術についての 仮説の作成。
Develop a hypothesis about their abilities
that can be drawn from
all these factors.
その確率と 選択…》
It's all about observation and analysis.
((神の裁きが下るぜ！))
God's judgment will be handed down!
God... judgment...
(シカマル)神… 裁き…。
((すでに テメエは オレに呪われた。
You have already fallen under my curse.
(これより儀式を始める))
The ceremony will now begin.
(シカマル)呪い… 儀式…。
A curse... the ceremony...
((これで すべての準備は整った))
With this, all preparations are complete!
(シカマル)準備…。
Preparations...!
《シカマルのヤツ…
何か考えついたようだな》
Looks like Shikamaru
came up with an idea.
何か わかったのか？ シカマル。
ああ。
Did you figure something out, Shikamaru?
Yeah!
《術をかけながらの この状態で➡
It's amazing that you're capable
of such an analysis
よく そんな分析を…》
while still maintaining your Jutsu.
《シカマルは 一瞬で十手先を➡
Shikamaru is endowed with
lightning powers of analysis
that enable him to look ten steps ahead
and predict 200 more.
200通り思考する素早い分析力と➡
What's more,
he has the intuition to choose
そこから最善の手を選び出す➡
the best possible strategy
based on that analysis.
勘を備えている》
I'm heading out, Captain Asuma...
いくぜ アスマ隊長。
《あの影の術…➡
That Shadow Jutsu...
対象者に 自分と同じ動きを
強制するのか…》
Does it force the person it's used on
to mirror the motions of its caster?
《コイツ 術の正体を…》
Why you... Trying to sniff out the true nature
of my Jutsu.
どうするんだ？
What are you going to do?!
I'll draw that creep outside the strange
pattern drawn on the ground!
あの 地面に描かれた
妙な図の中から➡
ヤツを 外へ引きずり出す。
そうすりゃ
ヤツの術… 呪いが解ける。
If I do that,
his curse Jutsu will be broken.
(イズモ)いったい どういうことだ？
What on earth does that mean?!
(シカマル)アイツの でかい武器…➡
His weapon...
３つも鎌がついてる。
That huge scythe with three blades.
形状からして あれは
必殺の一撃を狙う というより➡
Judging by its shape, I'd say it's not
designed to land a single fatal blow,
but rather increase
his attack range.
攻撃範囲を広くとり
とにかく相手に当てることで➡
All his weapons are designed to
cause damage from a distance.
大なり小なりの外傷を
与えることを➡
目的に作られている。
つまり 手傷一つ
負わせることができれば➡
In other words, his tactic is to
only injure his opponent
それで 確実に相手を殺せる術を
持ってるってことだ。
and then buy time to deploy
a lethal Jutsu.
それが呪いか？
And by that you mean the curse?
しかし 敵の手傷と呪いと➡
But what's the connection between
the enemy's wound and the curse?
どういう関係がある？
血だ…。
It's blood...
呪いたい相手とリンクするには
その相手の血を➡
In order to form a link between himself
and his targeted opponent,
he needs to find a way to incorporate
that opponent's blood into his own body.
自分の体内に
取り込む必要があるんだ。
ヤツが血を舐めるのを
オレも見た。
So when he was licking the blood...
(イズモ)そうか…
相手に外傷を与え➡
Then if he wounds his opponent and
even a little blood adheres to that sickle...
鎌に少しでも血が付着すれば➡
それで 相手を呪うことができる。
he can curse his opponent.
《なるほど…》
But of course...
After licking the blood,
his body changed color.
血を舐めたあと 体が変色した。
That is a condition for invoking the curse.
But that's not all.
その発動条件は
わかりやすかった。
だが それだけじゃない。
呪いの発動には もう一つの
わかりやすい条件があるのさ。
In order to completely invoke the curse,
one more condition must be met.
もう一つ？
One more?
《たいしたガキだ》
This brat knows his stuff.
さっきアイツは アスマの火遁の術を➡
A little while ago,
that creep let Asuma's Fire Style Jutsu
roll right off him.
無視してくらいながらでも➡
あの地面に描いた図の中へ
急いで戻っただろう？
He was unfazed,
but he hurried back to that strange pattern
drawn on the ground, remember?
そして その図の上で
儀式を始めると言い➡
And once he was standing
inside that pattern,
he said the ceremony would begin.
And by howling that the preparations
were now complete...
準備が整ったとほえたことで➡
アイツが あの図の中にいて
はじめて➡
We can surmise the set-up
for his art of cursing
is only complete once he steps
inside that pattern.
ようやく 呪いの術が
完成することが 推測できた。
(飛段)このガキ…。
You little brat!
アンタ… わめきすぎなんだよ。
You talk too much.
He was able to figure
all that out?
《ここまでの子とは…》
You little brat!
この ガキャ～！
Why you! I'll get you later!
I'll tear you limb from limb!
テメメ… あとで ギタギタのズタズタの
グチャグチャにしてやるぜ！
I'll pulverize you! I'll turn you inside out!
There isn't going to be a "later"!
あとなんて ねえよ！
ぐっ…。
We got him out!
出たぜ！
(アスマ)よし！
All right! The curse is broken!
術が解けたか 確かめる。
All right!
《よし！》
ぐっ…。
Wha--?!
野郎… 動けねえ。
Damnit...
I can't move...
(シカマル)もう これが限界っすよ。
I'm at my limit! I don't think
I can hold him any longer.
これ以上 もちそうもない。
You did well, Shikamaru.
よくやった シカマル。
Kakuzu! Lend me a hand!
角都！ 手を貸せ。
Hey! Snap to it!
こらっ！ さっさとしろ！
だから 気を抜くなと言ったのだ。
I told you to keep your wits
about you.
what made me think
kondo wa itsu aeru ka nante
how can you say that with a straight face
sonna kao shite yoku ieru tte
when you asked we will meet again
omotteta yo nande darou
any time you talk to much I don't get it
any time shaberisugi no k y
for a moment I see your bluff and I cry
chirari miseru tsuyogari na i cry
do my tears even work on you?
namida no kouka wa dore kurai
I keep saying "I want to be loved"
watashi nari ni aisaretai
in my own special way but you still don't get the hint
afureru no ni kimi ga mienai
this nagging feeling I feel
nidoto kimi ni aenai
that I'll never see you again...
sonna ki ga suru nda
I wish I could tell you but I can't find the words
tsutaetai no ni umai kotoba miataranai
maybe I'd rather listen to you lie
watashi tabun uso demo ii no ni
I can't even say "don't leave me"
ikanaide mo ienai yo
when you let go of my hand
nigitteta te ga hanaretara
will you forget someday?
kimi wa itsuka wasurechau no
about me
watashi no koto
I wish I could tell you but I can't find the words
tsutaetai no ni umai kotoba miataranai watashi tabun
お前… 前に 部屋が殺風景だって
言ってなかったか？
maybe I'd rather listen to you lie 'cause I can't even say "don't leave me"
uso demo ii no ni ikanaide mo ienai yo
(紅)えっ… そうだったかも
しれないけど。
これ… いのの オススメで
まあ よかったら。
Next Episode
All right! So this leaves
only one opponent remaining?
ポピーの種だそうだ。
But his power and speed are probably
greater than that of the immortal guy.
気持は うれしいけど
きっと枯らしちゃうわ。
And he may still have abilities
we don't know about...!
でも そんなに手はかからない
って話だぞ。
Shikamaru!
Shikamaru is exhausted.
でも…。
And the captain is wounded.
まあ…
気が向いたら 植えてみろよ。
What do you want to do, Izumo?
あっ！
We have the advantage of
outnumbering our opponents
もう…。
and even immobilized one of them.
結局 押しつけられちゃったな。
But perhaps we should start
looking for a chance to retreat.
Next time: "Unfulfilled Scream"
Unfulfilled Scream
気が向いたらって… このままじゃ
かわいそうじゃないの。
えっと ポピー ポピーっと…。
Weren't you saying something about
how drab the room was before?
Well, perhaps I did, but...
フフッ…。
花言葉は 「慰め」と 「いたわり」か。
Here. Ino suggested them.
Well, only if you like...
She said they were poppy seeds.
I appreciate your thoughtfulness,
but the plants would most likely
wither and die.
But I heard they don't
require much care.
Still...
Well, if you feel like it, try planting them!
I ended up getting this project
passed off on me.
Saying, "If you feel like it"
makes the poppy seeds seem so pitiful...
Let's see... poppies... poppies...
Huh?!
In the language of flowers, poppies signify
consolation and kind assistance.